The battle for eternity is the fantasy of a lifetime.
The Forbidden Kingdom is a action, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Rob Minkoff.
An American teenager who is obsessed with Hong Kong cinema and kung-fu classics makes an extraordinary discovery in
a Chinatown pawnshop: the legendary stick weapon of the Chinese sage and warrior, the Monkey King.
With the lost relic in hand, the teenager unexpectedly finds himself travelling back to ancient China to join a
crew of warriors from martial arts lore on a dangerous quest to free the imprisoned Monkey King.
Old Hop / Lu Yan, played by Jackie Chan.
The Silent Monk / The Monkey King, played by Jet Li.
Jason Tripitikas, played by Michael Angarano.
Golden Sparrow / Chinatown Girl, played by Liu Yifei.
Ni Chang a.k.a White-Haired Witch, played by Li Bingbing.
Jade Warlord, played by Collin Chou.
The Forbidden Kingdom (Chinese: 功夫之王: Gong Fu Zhi Wang (Mandarin) or Gung Fu Ji Wong (Cantonese) and translated King of Kung Fu (English); Working title: The J & J Project) is a
2008 fantasy wuxia film written by John Fusco and directed by Rob Minkoff, starring Jackie Chan, Jet Li, Michael Angarano, Liu Yifei, Collin Chou, and Li Bingbing.
Loosely based on the 16th-century Chinese novel Journey to the West, the plot revolves around Jason Tripitikas (Angarano), a
modern-day American teenager who is transported back to ancient China after discovering Sun Wukong's Ruyi Jingu Bang.
He accompanies Lu Yan (Chan), Silent Monk (Li), and Golden Sparrow (Yifei) on their quest to return the staff to its rightful
owner while trying to avoid the minions of the evil Jade Warlord (Chou) and the White-Haired Witch (Bingbing).
The action sequences were choreographed by Yuen Woo-ping.
The film is regarded as the first co-production helmed by an American director to make a
primarily English-language wuxia genre film set in ancient China for a global audience.
Heavily promoted as the first film starring both Chan and Li, it was distributed in the United States through
Lionsgate and The Weinstein Company, and through The Huayi Brothers Film & Taihe Investment Company in China.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed $128 million against a budget of $55 million.
The film explores themes of martial arts, based on
novel or book, temple, legend, villainess.